[Music]
what is up everyone my name would be
Josh this is straight in central and
today we are gonna be doing a product
review on the Lynx Eden so this is
actually the newest products from Lynx
vapor the successor to the Lynx Gaia I'm
sure most you guys had seen that or used
it but this is actually a convection
vaporizer is what they listed as after
playing around with it for a couple of
weeks I would personally say it's
probably mostly leaning towards
convection but does also offer more of
like a hybrid hit there is like a little
bit of conduction that happens with the
dry herb occasionally and if you guys
don't know the difference between
convection and conduction I explain this
all the time convection just think oven
it's like a box in which you put
something in and then it's cooked in the
box the the heats passed through
whatever it is and and it gets cooked
whereas conduction think stovetop like
conduction heating meaning it's directly
sitting on the heating source and it's
being heated directly you know on the
actual material so convection is more of
like you have material in the chamber
heats going through the material and
technically being vaporized conduction
it's sitting directly on the heating
source and it's getting you know heated
that way heated directly basically but
this is more of what I would say hybrid
leading towards convection that being
said you can use both dry herb and
concentrate in this so they actually do
include these small little things called
lava pads and what the lava pads are are
basically just screams so you can use
both at the same time so you don't have
to just use oil or just use dry herb
though you can you can actually
basically pack some like dry herb put
the lava plate on top of it put
concentrate on top of the lava plate and
then vape it all together to get
wholesome it flavor so this is
definitely gonna be a vape that is a lot
more of a flavor chaser like turf pen
then it really is gonna be a cloud pen
mostly just because it does have very
set temperature profiles and set
temperature settings that is something
I'll get to in just a second though guys
actually do have this thing going so I'm
gonna take a quick trip off it I
definitely hope you guys are smoking
along got a long vape along getting
those cab noise nice and deep into your
lungs cuz these are gonna be deep in
mine but cheers friends let's go ahead
and hits I am actually
can say on some Western cultured sour so
Cheers
[Music]
very light vapor production your first
couple hits but it does actually get the
heating up pretty pretty quickly you
[Music]
find a lot of convection pins then it
does actually take a couple of draws a
couple of pulls through it to kind of
get it really going as you do have to
actually kind of help it assist pulling
heat through the chamber but Cheers okay
first off stupid tasty that's one thing
I love about vaporizing is a lot of
people will say you don't get that like
crazy boom like hit to the head crazy
head change and that's mostly because
you're not inhaling large amounts of
carbon you're literally just vaporizing
cannabinoids so it usually does take a
little bit longer to onset and it also
is just a lot less vapor I'm not blowing
huge clouds of like I've said carbon I'm
literally specifically only inhaling the
things I need to be inhaling so you're
gonna get better flavor you're gonna get
a truer taste of the actual thing that
you're consuming and it's not
technically always gonna get you higher
vapes do sneak up on you though because
you'll just sit there hit them hit them
hit them hit them hit them and all of a
sudden you're in space and you didn't
even really realize it so I love babes
for stealthy like aspects stealthy
little sessions and then I also like
them for the flavor just because it
really does give you like the truest
taste of a strain I think I'm probably
gonna start incorporating more
vaporizers into strain reviews just to
kind of like really get those terpene
profiles dialed in
that all being said this is kind of
limiting in some ways when it comes to
terpenes as terpenes have very specific
set points in which they boil or which
they vaporize and realistically having a
pen like this that just has temperature
settings doesn't really allow you to
have like the full range of choosing
exactly where you want to be so the for
temperature settings they have the
lowest setting is actually 360 360
degrees Fahrenheit the second setting is
380 degrees Fahrenheit the third setting
is 400 degrees Fahrenheit and then the
fourth one is 428 degrees Fahrenheit you
couldn't could drop us the 420 there
come on you couldn't drop that 8 degrees
and just give us the 420 that we all
wanted actually I think that's what
they're still trying to do I think they
probably wanted to make it 4:30 but they
were like if we add those extra two it's
technically not 420 anymore I have been
mostly using this on the red setting
though which is the highest setting so
that 428 just because I personally do
like to vaporize a little bit higher and
get a little bit more vapor production
on most of my hips so when it comes to
the battery itself this actually is a
2500 milliamp hour battery and it does
have about I think a 0.5 amp charge rate
so it takes a long long long time to
charge I want to say a normal charging
session for this is anywhere between
probably like 4 to 6 hours it does have
USB C charging so technically it is in
like that new-age charging that being
said it's a pretty big battery and with
that really low amp rate it's it's not
something that charges quickly so you
will be able to use this for quite a
while you're able to get quite a few
probably like between 20 to 30 sessions
off this normally before it actually
does fully die but once it dies it takes
quite a long time to actually charge and
it cannot be used while it's charging so
the body itself is actually steel as you
can see it's a really sturdy and I would
actually also say really stealthy unit
this is a unit that I think a lot of
people would just write off as an e-cig
seeing someone use this you're not
immediately thinking oh that's a weed
vapor oh that person's definitely
they've been weed like you would
probably more than likely think it's
just one of those really big ridiculous
ecig mods the
we use so you definitely have that under
your belts though vaporizers don't
reduce the smell of cannabis in any way
really it makes it slightly less burnt
smelling but it still smells like weed
no matter what so cheers guys we'll hit
this one more time the other last thing
I will say kind of regarding flavor is
really quickly the mouthpiece so it does
have a glass mouthpiece and a fully core
chamber which basically maximizes that
kind of flavor really dialing in to
specifically get you the most flavor and
they actually do include three
replaceable mouth police police
tips mouthpiece tips that's almost like
a tongue twister which is really handy
because on the gaia I actually broke a
couple of the tips so including
replacements is definitely something
that they made specifically through in
there because they have the other heard
cons from the gaya or have broken tips
themselves really smart move guys but
Cheers I'm rambling I'm ranting but
that's what this hour always gets me to
so let's get it
[Music]
so I've always loved links I've always
loved working with links just because
they're one of those companies that well
first off they're all consumers
themselves so they actually do use their
products they aren't just pushing out
you know some rebranded pin with their
name on it and then trying to market it
the best they can they're innovating
they're actually kind of specifically
getting different parts of the market
this is more of a cheap pen it's under a
hundred dollars or I think it's like
right at a hundred dollars so it's not
one of those you know specifically fancy
store and Bickel pens or you know one of
the larger brands that you're gonna be
spending six seven hundred dollars on a
pen that being said they do also offer
things like the gaia that does kind of
specifically cater to that audience so
they do have cheap pens for people who
don't want to spend an arm and a leg
they do have more expensive pens they
have wax pens they have herb pens they
cater to every aspect of consumptions
because they're consumers themselves and
that's something that that is a recipe
in my opinion for innovation they also
don't take negatively to a pros and cons
list they listen to the cons they
improve on the cons and they actually
release products like this so I am super
stoked on that that's one of the biggest
reasons I have like really wanted to
continue to work with them and have
worked with them for so long and when it
comes to flavor I don't think I've used
a lot of pens that do compete with
something like this I think this is
probably gonna be one of my new go-to
pens for straighter views just because I
can put wax in it I can put all my flour
in it and with the quartz / glass kind
of like chamber system it provides
really phenomenal flavor alright so when
it this is one more time and then I'll
actually get into the pros and cons guys
so Cheers
oh the flavor is still phenomenal - okay
so breaking down the pros and the cons
I'm gonna probably do the cons first
just because I have a lot less of those
with this thing so the number one con is
something that I kind of already covered
in the battery section it's just really
slow charging this thing takes forever
to actually get charged and if you're
like getting ready to actually leave and
forgot to charge it it's not gonna be
something that you can bring with you as
it takes forever to actually get charged
the second thing is going to be kind of
a not-so-great con as it doesn't hold
with the price I think that the four
temp settings for the price is pretty
reasonable that all being said
especially as a device that's really
specifically for flavor with the courts
on the glass I think that having a fully
dialed in temp setting might be
something someone wants so because you
can't dial it in specifically by the
degree I'm gonna give it a technical con
for that and then the last con I do see
what this is the mouthpiece itself does
get really hot it's something that it
does take a little bit of time but
because it's glass and because it's so
close to the heating element because
it's convection a lot of things together
do make it so after a couple of hits
your your lips are definitely gonna feel
this mouthpiece getting hotter and
hotter and hotter and hotter
so after maybe like six seven draws
you're gonna have to stop hitting it or
else it's gonna like borderline burn
your lip so maybe a silicon mouthpiece
of something for that would definitely
be another huge like plus a huge
positive but going into the actual pros
with this there's a lot more pros than
there are cons it's super easy to use
it's super easy to clean and it's really
reasonably priced a hundred dollars for
update that does both actual herb and
concentrate and it's gonna last you a
long time is a huge pro the entire
quartz-like chamber system makes it so a
single iso q-tip rubbing that thing
around you're good to go you're perp
you guys all know that I do personally
lean towards that like convection bait
side of things
I prefer convection babes over
conduction babes so that's my last big
Pro at this thing is just it straight up
kills it as a at the very least hybrid
convection vaporizer that all being said
I think that is just about all I do have
for this episode so I definitely hope
you guys enjoyed this quick little
review on the eating I'm more more more
hopefully hope more hopefully hope I'm
not high what are you talking about i
more than hopefully hope i don't even
know what the actual sentence I'm
looking for is there's a sentence here
I'm looking for and it's not coming to
my brain so I definitely hope you guys
an absolutely incredible one and more
importantly I definitely help if
anything's going rough today if you guys
are having a shitty day that you're able
to keep that head up and remember that
tomorrow will bring a better one more
importantly keep fighting keep pushing
keep working towards things and that's
how you see change that's how you see
things get better it doesn't come just
sitting around and waiting so cheers
guys one more rip off this
[Music]
stay positive stay medicated peace guys